A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Religious Interests, Series N FA323
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Churches
  - Churches - Glenville Congregational Church, Glenville, Ohio, 1910-1912 (Box 24, Folder 167)
    Contribution to building fund of church by John D. Rockefeller. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Albert Eby, J. G. W. Cowles.
  - Churches - Greenville Methodist Episcopal Church, Lakewood, New Jersey, 1927-1928 (Box 24, Folder 168)
    Letters of thanks for donations from John D. Rockefeller. Gifts to Ladies' Aid Society and for parsonage debt. Correspondents include E. V. Cary, Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller, N. W. Davis, Robert W. Gumbel, Arthur W. Packard.
  - Churches - Holy Cross Parish, New York City, 1927-1928 (Box 24, Folder 169)
    Gift to parish to celebrate Diamond Jubilee. Correspondents include Rev. Francis P. Duffy, Thomas B. Appleget, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Churches - Hyde Park Baptist Church, Chicago, Illinois, 1901-1906 (Box 24, Folder 170)
    Gift to church for University of Chicago students. Correspondents include William R. Harper, Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Churches - First Baptist Church, Hastings-on-Hudson, New York, 1905 (Box 24, Folder 171)
    John D. Rockefeller's gift to liquidate church debt, church to raise most of necessary funds. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller.
  - Churches - Immaculate Conception Roman Catholic Church, Tarrytown, New York, 1918-1957 (Box 24, Folder 172)
    John D. Rockefeller's gift to Italian-American church destroyed by fire. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s gift for building fund, policy on contributions to Catholic churches in Tarrytown. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Willard S. Richardson, Father D. M. Gader, Arthur W. Packard.
  - Churches - Istrouma Baptist Church, Baton Rouge, Louisiana, 1930-1938 (Box 24, Folder 173)
    Interest in completion of building to which John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributed, gift to minister, further request declined. List of pledges. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Robert W. Gumbel, C. J. Hicks, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Churches - John Street Church, New York City, 1925-1941 (Box 25, Folder 175)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gift to church. Later declinations. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Thomas B. Appleget, Robert W. Gumbel.
  - Churches - Judson Memorial Baptist Church, New York City, 1899-1910 (Box 25, Folder 176)
    John D. Rockefeller pledges for minister's salary, relief of poor summer work. Contributions toward church debt. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. special purpose gifts, message at opening of neighborhood house. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Frederick T. Gates, Willard S. Richardson.
  - Churches - Judson Memorial Baptist Church, New York City, 1911-1919 (Box 25, Folder 177)
  - Churches - Kent's Corner Church, Riverside, Rhode Island, 1945-1947 (Box 25, Folder 178)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. anonymous gift. Later declinations. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard.
  - Churches - Lantern League of the Old North Church, Boston, Massachusetts, 1933-1961 (Box 25, Folder 179)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd gives $250 to aid in preservation of church. League referred to Williamsburg for restoration advice in 1952. Steeple destroyed in 1954 hurricane. Appeals to family all declined. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Churches - Lantern League of the Old North Church, Boston, Massachusetts, 1954 (Box 25, Folder 179A)
  - Churches - Madison Avenue Presbyterian Church, 1939-1954 (Box 25, Folder 180)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd contributions. Attendance of children in Sunday School. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Nelson A. Rockefeller, George Buttrick.
  - Churches - Marble Collegiate Church, 1933-1957 (Box 25, Folder 181)
    Declining invitations to speak before church groups. Correspondents include Norman V. Peale, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Francis A. Jamieson, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Churches - Marble Collegiate Church - American Foundation of Religion and Psychiatry, 1951-1961 (Box 25, Folder 182)
    Clinic founded by Dr. Norman V. Peale, Dr. S. Blanton.
  - Churches - Mariner's Temple, 1927-1949 (Box 25, Folder 183)
    Appeal for funds from Old Mariner's Church of New York Port Society, denied. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Robert W. Gumbel, Thomas B. Appleget.
  - Churches - Medina Baptist Church, 1906-1910 (Box 25, Folder 184)
    John D. Rockefeller's gift toward church indebtedness, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s gift to former Sunday School teacher for church construction fund. Correspondents include Charles F. Lang, George D. Rogers, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Mrs. N. O. Fuller.
  - Churches - Methodist Episcopal Church, Whiting, Indiana, 1904-1905 (Box 25, Folder 185)
    Church needs to town of Whiting. John D. Rockefeller's confidential contribution to church. Correspondents include W. P. Cowan, John D. Rockefeller, Starr J. Murphy, Bertram Cutler.
  - Churches - Mount Morris Baptist Church, 1903-1914 (Box 25, Folder 186)
    John D. Rockefeller gift to church debt in 1903. Later requests declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Frederick T. Gates.
  - Churches - Mount Olivet Baptist Church, 1927-1940 (Box 25, Folder 187)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s loan to church for indebtedness - payment of loan. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt, J. F. Comey, G. D. Rogers, Thomas B. Appleget, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, W. R. Conklin, Thomas M. Debevoise, Willard S. Richardson, Phillip Keebler.
  - Churches - Mount Olivet Baptist Church - John D. Rockefeller Contributions, 1901-1904 (Box 25, Folder 188)
    Lists of pledges.
  - Churches - National Cathedral, Washington, D. C., 1920-1960 (Box 26, Folder 189)
    Appeals for aid in building Episcopal Cathedral. Restriction of members of Board of Trustees to Episcopalians. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. objections to narrow provisions. Decision not to contribute. Consistent declinations. Descriptions of Cathedral progress. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur Woods, Anson P. Stokes.
  - Churches - National Cathedral, Washington, D. C. - Pamphlets, 1919-1946 (Box 26, Folder 190)
  - Churches - Ormond Union Church, 1919-1959 (Box 26, Folder 191)
    John D. Rockefeller contributes to building fund, other special contributions. Final contribution in 1938. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Frank Abrams, Theodore Rogers.
  - Churches - Ormond Union Church - Dr. George D. Owen, 1929-1936 (Box 26, Folder 192)
    Payment of Mr. Owen's salary by John D. Rockefeller.
  - Churches - Plymouth Congregational Church, Cleveland, Ohio, 1899-1912 (Box 26, Folder 193)
    John D. Rockefeller's gift to liquidate church debt, denial of assistance in meeting current expenses. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, Frederick T. Gates, J. G. W. Cowles.
  - Churches - Russian Orthodox Church, 1925-1953 (Box 26, Folder 194)
    Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) reports on religious situation in Russia, aid to present and prospective leaders of Orthodox Church in the Russian emigration. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s donation to strengthen program. Church at Nyack, no assistance to Russian Orthodox Church in Washington, D. C. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., J. R. Mott.
  - Churches - Russian Orthodox Churches in New York, 1937-1958 (Box 26, Folder 195)
    Request for aid, declined. Russian St. Nicholas Church in Washington, D. C. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Arthur W. Packard, Yorke Allen, Edgar P. Young, Dana S. Creel.
  - Churches - St. Mark's Episcopal Church, Tarrytown, New York, 1920-1949 (Box 26, Folder 196)
    John D. Rockefeller donations for specific projects. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s declinations. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Churches - St. Paul's Methodist Church, Tarrytown, New York, 1914-1917 (Box 27, Folder 197)
    John D. Rockefeller's donations. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. declinations. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Churches - Santa Barbara Reconstruction Committee, 1925-1926 (Box 27, Folder 198)
    Appeal for aid in rebuilding Protestant churches after earthquake. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledged $10,000 toward work. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Churches - St. Mary's Church, Scarborough, New York, 1934-1961 (Box 27, Folder 199)
    Appeal to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. on basis of William Rockefeller's association with church declined. Appeals to John D. Rockefeller 3rd. John D. Rockefeller 3rd made occasional gifts to church for special purposes. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Jay Downer, Myron C. Taylor.
  - Churches - St. Paul's Church, Eastchester, New York, 1936-1949 (Box 27, Folder 200)
    Appeal to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to aid in restoration of 18th Century church building, declined. Church restored and made a national shrine. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Jay Downer, Myron C. Taylor.
  - Churches - St. Paul's Church, Eastchester, New York, 1941-1942 (Box 27, Folder 200A)
  - Churches - Scarborough Presbyterian Church, 1944-1960 (Box 27, Folder 201)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd's gift toward replacement of capital equipment, repairs and redecoration program, Organ Fund. $5,000 to Sunday School Fund. Correspondents include John F. McPherson, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Arthur W. Packard, Rev. Robert P. Montgomery.
  - Churches - Second Reformed Church, Tarrytown, New York, 1904-1950 (Box 27, Folder 202)
    John D. Rockefeller's gift to church, 1904-1935, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s beliefs in cooperation and consolidation among Tarrytown's churches. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, G. D. Rogers, Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, John D. Rockefeller.
  - Churches - Shiloh Baptist Church, Tarrytown, New York, 1897-1933 (Box 27, Folder 203)
    John D. Rockefeller gifts for debt payments and furnishings. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gifts for building and organ repairs. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Willard S. Richardson, Arthur W. Packard.
  - Churches - Shiloh Baptist Church, Tarrytown, New York, 1936-1956 (Box 27, Folder 204)
  - Churches - Church of the Highlands - Fred B. Smith Memorial, 1937-1938 (Box 27, Folder 205)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s pledge for community house, conditions of gift. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, James H. Post.
  - Churches - Swedish Lutheran Churches, Hibbing, Minnesota, 1899 (Box 27, Folder 206)
    Appeals to John D. Rockefeller for aid, handled by Frederick T. Gates, declined. Correspondents include Frederick T. Gates.
  - Churches - Swedish Lutheran Churches, Duluth, Minnesota, 1907, 1922 (Box 27, Folder 207)
  - Churches - Tabernacle Baptist Church (Institutional), Augusta, Georgia, 1908-1947 (Box 27, Folder 208)
    Anonymous gift to church for instruction of Negroes. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Frederick T. Gates, Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Churches - Tokyo Union Church, 1923-1930, 1952-1954 (Box 27, Folder 209)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s pledge, other gifts. John D. Rockefeller 3rd's contributions. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Edgar B. Young.
  - Churches - Trinity Baptist Church, Cleveland, Ohio, 1904-1908 (Box 27, Folder 210)
    John D. Rockefeller provides funds for missionary for church. Other requests, declined or ignored. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller.
  - Churches - Union Baptist Church, New York City, 1928-1948 (Box 28, Folder 211)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. guarantee of bank loan for Negro church. Anonymous gifts to pay off debts. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Willard S. Richardson.
  - Churches - Union Church of Guatemala, 1948-1952 (Box 28, Folder 212)
    Appeals for aid declined. Correspondents include Dana S. Creel.
  - Churches - Union of Churches of Christ, Kingston, New York, 1939-1958 (Box 28, Folder 213)
    Organization to carry Protestant Christianity to Russia and Poland. Also to carry on missionary work among Slavs in United States. No family interest. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel.
  - Churches - Union Church of Pocantico Hills
    Call of ministers, dedication of new building, contributions by John D. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr.; pulpit supply, maintenance, supplies for parsonage, ministers' personal problems. Board membership of John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd. Contributions by family members. Nelson A. Rockefeller a trustee. Brief history of church. Rockefellers supplied about 50% of the budget of the church. Five generations of Rockefellers connected with the church. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., J. Homer Nelson, Lester Bent, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, Willard S. Richardson, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, Grandchildren.
    - 1909-1926 (Box 28, Folder 214)
    - 1927-1939 (Box 28, Folder 215)
    - 1940-1951 (Box 28, Folder 216)
    - 1952-1955 (Box 28, Folder 217)
    - 1956-1961 (Box 29, Folder 218)
    - 1956-1961 (Box 29, Folder 218A)
      Conditions Governing Access note
      Restricted - Living Rockefeller family - Restricted for Life
  - Additions to Parish Hall
    - 3 Surveys of Old and New Property Lines of Union Church- Pocantico Hills., 1929 July; December; BLUEPRINT (Quantity 3) (Drawer B 1, Folder 90)
    - Union of P.H Comm. Center; addition to parish hall. Wyeth & King Architects (see correspondence 1954, April 27), 1955 January 17; ARCHITECTURAL DRAWING (Quantity 6) (Drawer B 1, Folder 90)
    - Topographical Survey prepared for Union Church of Pocantico Hills, 1954 April 6; MAP (Quantity 1) (Drawer B 1, Folder 90)
    - Survey of property prepared for Union Church of Pocantico Hills (4 copies) Note attached to first page from J.Farrell to Mr. Gumbel, 1954 September 20. (Chas H. Sells), 1954 July; MAP (Quantity 4) (Drawer B 1, Folder 90)
    - Sketch plan showing proposed children's building as an addition to the parish hall and suggested road layout. (see correspondences of 1954 November 22-23), RENDERING (Quantity 1) (Drawer B 1, Folder 90)
    - photocopies of "Addition to parish hall," Union Church. (Wyeth & King Architects), 1954 November 23; ARCHITECTURAL DRAWING (Quantity 3) (Drawer B 1, Folder 90)
    - Site plan showing proposed children's building as an addition to the parish hall and suggested road layout. Union Church-Pocantico Hills (Wyeth & King Architects), 1955 January 17; MAP (Quantity 4) (Drawer B 1, Folder 90)
    - "Alteration and additions to parish hall," Union Church-Pocantico Hills-Final report to advisory board from the Building committee, 1955 May 31; ARCHITECTURAL DRAWING (Quantity 5) (Drawer B 1, Folder 90)
    - Survey of parsonage lot belonging to JDR Jr. (scale 1" = 50') (Walter Kidde Constructors Inc.), 1938 June; MAP (Quantity 1) (Drawer B 1, Folder 90)
    - Survey of portion of Magee lot prepared for JDR Jr. (scale 1" = 2') (Walter Kidde Constructors Inc.), 1938 October; BLUEPRINT (Quantity 1) (Drawer B 1, Folder 90)
  - Churches - Union Church of Pocantico Hills - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Memorial, 1955-1960 (Box 29, Folder 219)
    Matisse stained glass window and a plaque for memorial. Suggested window in memory of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Churches - Union Church of Pocantico Hills - 50th Anniversary, 1940 (Box 29, Folder 220)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. letter to Rufus Jones to be speaker, arrangements for speakers. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contributions toward expenses.
  - Churches - Union Church of Pocantico Hills - Budgets, 1941, 1948, 1960-1961 (Box 29, Folder 221)
    1961 material retained.
  - Churches - Union Church of Pocantico Hills - Changes in Church Constitution, 1915, 1941-1949, 1959 (Box 29, Folder 222)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s offer to defray expenses of printing by-laws and history. Correspondents include V. Webb, W. J. Conklin, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Morgan Johnson.
  - Churches - Union Church of Pocantico Hills - Correspondence re: Clock, 1934-1951 (Box 29, Folder 223)
    Maintenance of church clock (John D. Rockefeller, Jr. memorial to his mother), payment of bills. Correspondents include Robert W. Gumbel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Churches - Union Church of Pocantico Hills - Insurance, 1924-1947 (Box 29, Folder 224)
    Costs.
  - Churches - Union Church of Pocantico Hills - Memorial Tablet, John D. Rockefeller, 1940-1941 (Box 29, Folder 225)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s comments about wording, contributions, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s satisfaction, payment of sculptor's fees. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Robert W. Gumbel, Mott B. Schmitt, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller, Emile Sieburn.
  - Churches - Union Church of Pocantico Hills - Minutes of Meetings, 1941, 1960-1961 (Box 29, Folder 226)
  - Churches - Union Church of Pocantico Hills - Rev. George B. Owen, 1942-1949 (Box 29, Folder 227)
    Christmas gifts to minister, his retirement, farewell gift, death of Mrs. Owen.
  - Churches - Union Church of Pocantico Hills - Rev. L. H. Bent, 1933-1937 (Box 29, Folder 228)
  - Churches - Union Church of Pocantico Hills - Parsonage, 1929-1930 (Box 29, Folder 229)
    Cost of parsonage, contribution, details.
  - Churches - Union Church of Pocantico Hills - Community Center, 1954-1957 (Box 30, Folder 230)
    Plans for center, David Rockefeller chairman of committee. Construction. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pays expenses. Dedication. Plaque for building. Correspondents include David Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    Related Archival Materials note
    Blueprints and plans in map case.
  - Churches - Union Church of Pocantico Hills - February 1956 Pledge for Church Addition, 1954-1958 (Box 30, Folder 231)
    Pledge $200,000 for church addition.
  - Churches - Union Church of Pocantico Hills - Constitution, 1915-1922, 1949 (Box 30, Folder 232)
    Historical sketch of early Christian work at Pocantico Hills. 1915 discussion of incorporation. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s thoughts on establishing a union church. Membership qualifications. Final incorporation in 1922. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Willard S. Richardson, J. H. Nelson.
  - Churches - Union Church of Pocantico Hills - Contributions
    John D. Rockefeller made first pledge to religious work at Pocantico Hills in 1901, agreed to pay one half of cost. Agreed to also pay part of minister's salary and supply a manse. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. also contributes to minister's salary. Gifts for special occasions. Sustaining gifts by all members of the family. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller, David Milton.
    - 1902-1932 (Box 30, Folder 233)
    - 1933-1941 (Box 30, Folder 234)
    - 1942-1961 (Box 30, Folder 235)
  - Churches - Union Church of Pocantico Hills - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Contributions, 1927-1960 (Box 31, Folder 236)
    Annual gifts ranging from $700 to $4,000.
  - Churches - Union Church of Pocantico Hills - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Contributions, 1942-1960 (Box 31, Folder 236A)
  - Churches - Union Church of Pocantico Hills - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Memorial Scholarship Fund, 1960-1961 (Box 31, Folder 237)
    Church members desire to set up $10,000 fund for scholarships in memory of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Raised $2,500. Additional $2,500 given anonymously. Management of fund. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Dana S. Creel.
  - Churches - Union Church of Pocantico Hills - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Memorial Scholarship Fund, 1960 (Box 31, Folder 237A)
  - Churches - Union Church of Pocantico Hills - Deeds of Land, 1922-1938 (Box 31, Folder 238)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gifts of land to church. Copies of conveyances.
    Separated Materials note
    Blueprint of survey, July and December 1922, and June and October 1938 removed to map case.
  - Churches - Walker Memorial Baptist Church, New York City, 1936-1946 (Box 31, Folder 239)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s assistance in paying expenses re church litigation. Correspondents include W. G. Conklin, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Churches - Washington Heights Baptist Church, 1902-1905, 1912 (Box 31, Folder 240)
    John D. Rockefeller avoids involvement in struggle between city mission society and church. Pledge for debt, unredeemed. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Frederick T. Gates, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy.
  - Churches - Westminster Presbyterian Church (formerly Madison Avenue Presbyterian Church), Cleveland, Ohio, 1906-1908 (Box 31, Folder 241)
    Cleveland, Ohio. John D. Rockefeller gives $5,000 toward new building. Correspondents include Frederick T. Gates, Starr J. Murphy.
  - Churches - Willson Avenue Baptist Church, Cleveland, Ohio, 1900-1904 (Box 31, Folder 242)
    List of John D. Rockefeller's contributions to this church. Correspondents include G. H. Chandler, John D. Rockefeller.
  - Churches - Windermere Methodist Episcopal Church, Cleveland, Ohio., 1905-1947 (Box 31, Folder 243)
    Statement of church financial needs, John D. Rockefeller's gift toward building fund, later appeals declined. Correspondents include Rev. N. W. Stroup, willard S. Richardson, Rev. W. Stanley Smith, Rev. M. Wayne McQueen, Arthur W. Packard.
  - Churches - Yokohama Union Church, 1924-1927 (Box 31, Folder 244)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s gift to rebuild church destroyed by earthquake. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Rev. Herbert Manchester.
  - Churches - E. S. Jones Article - Church Unity, 1935 (Box 31, Folder 245)
    Two copies of article, "Christians of America, Unite!" (From Christian Century, October 2, 1935.)
- Federal Council of Churches of Christ in America
  - Federal Council of Churches of Christ in America
    John D. Rockefeller's pledge to Federation, renewal, contribution to inter-church conference on federation, work of Council, industrial relations, letters of thanks for reports on deportation, publication of Federal Coal Commission's report. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s testimonial letter to Frank Goodman, prayer for January 1, 1944, Day of Prayer, work of Council. Correspondents include Charles Evans Hughes, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller, Willard S. Richardson, Arthur W. Packard, Raymond B. Fosdick.
    73
    - 1900-1920 (Box 31, Folder 246)
    - 1921-1934 (Box 31, Folder 247)
    - 1935-1946 (Box 32, Folder 248)
    - 1947-1951 (Box 32, Folder 249)
  - Federal Council of Churches of Christ in America - Committee on Marriage and the Home, 1932-1940 (Box 32, Folder 250)
    Work of the Committee, financial statement, pledge to Committee in Mrs. Rockefeller's name. Correspondents include Worth M. Tippy, Arthur W. Packard, Robert W. Gumbel, L. Foster Wood.
  - Federal Council of Churches of Christ in America - Committee on Religion and Medicine, 1927-1940 (Box 32, Folder 251)
    Proposed study, denial of appeals for contributions. Correspondents include Mrs. John Sherman Hoyt, Arthur W. Packard, Nelson A. Rockefeller.
  - Federal Council of Churches of Christ in America - National Preaching Mission, 1936-1940 (Box 32, Folder 252)